<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raffi Hovhannesian</title>
    <description>Blogging about web development technologies plus some tips and tricks.</description>
    <link>http://hovhannesian.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://hovhannesian.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 05:34:57 +0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 05:34:57 +0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>1-2 Hours And Your Blog is Ready</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In fact it took more than two hours to create this blog that you are reading right now, but that included doing several other tasks like fixing some issues on a client&#39;s site, browsing facebook, writing this article and fixing the kitchen&#39;s curtain for my mom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;What You Need&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Terminal window&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Text editor&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Github Account&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Disqus Account&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A Domain Name (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have everything needed. Let&#39;s start building our blog system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Installing Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Jekyll is an open source program, written in Ruby by Tom Preston-Werner, GitHub&#39;s co-founder. Jekyll is a simple, blog-aware, static site generator for personal, project, or organization sites. --Wikipedia&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the installation steps mentioned on &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot; title=&quot;Jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&#39;s Official Website&lt;/a&gt; do the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
gem install jekyll
jekyll new my-awesome-site
cd my-awesome-site
jekyll serve
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your browser address bar type http://0.0.0.0:4000 or whatever address jekyll serve provides and hit enter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oops the blog is ready! It took less than a minute! But I promised you that you will spend two hours, so let&#39;s repeat the above 120 times :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, what we did is that we just made sure that jekyll is working with no issues. Go ahead and explore the code in my-awesome-site folder. When you feel ready continue to the next steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Installing a  Bootstrap Powered Jekyll Theme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Googling for Jekyll themes I came across many beautiful themes from which I chose the following one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/IronSummitMedia/startbootstrap-clean-blog-jekyll&quot; title=&quot;Startbootstrap Clean Blog Jekyll&quot;&gt;https://github.com/IronSummitMedia/startbootstrap-clean-blog-jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;So, let&#39;s install it:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you &lt;code&gt;cd ..&lt;/code&gt; out of the previously installed folder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
git clone https://github.com/IronSummitMedia/startbootstrap-clean-blog-jekyll.git
mv startbootstrap-clean-blog-jekyll mysite
cd mysite
jekyll serve
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to http://0.0.0.0:4000 again and you will see our blog with the new theme&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Modify the Theme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are familiar with Bootstrap and LESS which I assume you are ... you can simply modify the files in the &quot;less&quot; folder in the root of &quot;mysite&quot; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Main Configuration and Personalization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With your favourite text editor open the &quot;_config.yml&quot; file and edit the values under #site settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Adding Your First Post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in the folder named &quot;_layouts&quot; you will find all the posts in the blog as a file for each post. You will probably want to delete all of them and leave just one as a template for your future posts. Edit the template that&#39;s left and make sure you keep the naming conversion yyyy-mm-dd-page-title-seperated-with-hypens.markdown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Creating the Comment funcationality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you don&#39;t have an account on &lt;a href=&quot;disqus.com&quot;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt;, create one. Then follow the instructions on &lt;a href=&quot;https://publishers.disqus.com/engage?utm_source=Home-Nav&quot;&gt;https://publishers.disqus.com/engage?utm_source=Home-Nav&lt;/a&gt; until you get the embedding code. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
With your editor open the file &quot;_layouts/post.html&quot; and put the embedding code before the forth closing div from bottom.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Uploading your site to github&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Follow the instructions on this page https://pages.github.com/
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
That&#39;s all for today... let me know which point needs to be described more extensively and I&#39;ll write a seperate post for it. Thanks for reading.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photograph by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/nasacommons/&quot;&gt;NASA on The Commons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 16:00:00 +0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://hovhannesian.com/2015/09/12/create-blog-in-two-hours/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hovhannesian.com/2015/09/12/create-blog-in-two-hours/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
